CURRICULUM VITAE

I have done some volentering where I gained valuable experience in the work invironment. I have strong attention to detail and inclination for problem-solving. To build upon this interest, I have recently graduated from a coding Traineeship as a full stack developer including completing 2 real-world projects successfully to specification using a wide range of programming languages. I have excellent customer service, communication, teamwork and organisation skills and a strong work ethic. I enjoy learning new concepts, and problem solving. I am looking forward to establishing a career in the development field where I can prove myself as an asset.

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: Kiran Sundal

RESIDES: Walsall

TRANSPORT: Public transport

CONTACT DETAILS: (M) 07732 190028

(E) kmsundal@gmail.com
(W) https://kiransundal.co.uk/

(GH) https://github.com/KiranS22/ (please email to request access)

(LI) https://www.linkedin.com/in/kiran-sundal-ba3672212/

CODING TRAINEESHIP IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship - Full stack developer

1-year program

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills

• HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

- PHP, SQL, React, jQuery
- Java, Python, C#, Node.js
- Command Line Git, GitHub
- Remote API access

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES:

 Bootstrap, PostgreSQl, Express.js, Redux, Linux, Apache, MySQL, Powershell, GitBash, Visual Studio Code, PgAdmin, PHPMyAdmin, Postman, Netlify, Slack

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE:

Below are the two briefs of development projects I completed with IT Career Switch which can be found in my bio: https://kiransundal.co.uk/

Portfolio Project #1: "Gazetteer"

The specification was to reply to a website specification for a map-based app to provide information on countries — with a focus on a "mobile-first" development. Preferably using a framework, to then develop HTML, CSS and JavaScript with JQuery modules that use PHP server-based components to source data from third-party APIs (Geonames, OpenWeather). The solution is assessed on its delivery to specification, functionality, and usability.

Portfolio Project #2: "Company Directory"

A more rigorous reply to this specification was required as a user requirements document was needed to be prepared which, when signed off, triggers the release of SQL allowing to develop a "mobile first" application to maintain a company personnel database (MySQL). Sign-off is only achieved upon the student supplying an independently witnessed document providing confirmation of the system's ability to perform error-free.

CAREER HISTORY:

VOLUNTEER WORK:

July 2018 – Jan 2019 POSITION HELD:

WHG

Work Placement (Health and Wellbeing Team)

- Engaged with customers by email, letter, text and telephone
- Received and processed referrals
- Provided relevant advice and guidance to customers
- Various admin tasks for wider Health and Wellbeing Team

Nov 2017 – June 2018 POSITION HELD:

Healthy Living Centre Work Experience

- Assisted with administrative tasks
- Produced marketing material
- Typed letters
- Produced information packs
- Made and received phone calls

Sept 2016 – Sept 2017 POSITION HELD:

Lindens Primary School Work Experience

EDUCATION:

2016 - Present

Walsall College

BTEC Extended Diploma in Health and Social Care Level 3

(Grade: Distinction*)
GCSE English (Grade: 5)

Diploma in Business Administration

The Streetly Academy

Nine GCSEs (Grade: $A^* - C$)